<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neural Networks on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neural Networks on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Neural Networks? Why do we use them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/neural-networks-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/neural-networks-overview/</guid>
      <description>Why do we use neural networks? Neural networks help us solve a lot of complicated problems when there&amp;rsquo;s no clear way to solve it. Sometimes problems can be complicated enough where we don&amp;rsquo;t know how to solve it, or solving them in conventional way will lead to very complicated algorithms which cannot adapt to changes.
Neural networks play essential role in acting like human brain - helping us solving problems which we are good at: speech recognition, object recognition, pattern recognition, classification, etc&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks: Supervised, Unsupervised &amp; Reinforcement Learning Types of Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/neural-networks-types-of-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/neural-networks-types-of-learning/</guid>
      <description>There are 3 types of learning
 Supervised learning Reinforcement learning Unsupervised learning  Supervised Learning In supervised learning we try to predict an output when given an input vector. Input and target are clear in supervised learning.
Regression - target ouptut is a real numbers or a vector of real numbers
Classification - target output is a class label
Model-class is a function:
\begin{equation} y = f(x; W) \end{equation}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 2.7: Setting up Neural Network with PyBrain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/machine-learning-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ml-neural-networks/machine-learning-python/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting machine learning concepts in python. For this purchase I&amp;rsquo;m using PyBrain. If you would like to have a better idea about Python, I suggest having a quick glance at posts 1-10 in Python category.
PyBrain is a Machine Learning library for Python. PyBrain stands for Python-Based Reinforcemnet Learning, Artificial Intelligence and Neural Network Library.
For complete guide on installation you can get complete details from:
http://pybrain.org/docs/
In the example below, based on pybrain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>